<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><sentences><item><sentiment_score>0.5</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>309</sentence_id><sentence_number>309</sentence_number><text>70 : On Weaving outstanding examples of textile art.</text><page>70</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.5</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>230</sentence_id><sentence_number>230</sentence_number><text>(For more details see Raoul d&apos; Harcourt, Textiles of</text><page>53</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>-0.062</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>188</sentence_id><sentence_number>188</sentence_number><text>By taking up textile fundamentls and methods, I hoped to include in my audience not only weavers but also those whose work in other fields encompasses textile problems.</text><page>13</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>17</sentence_id><sentence_number>17</sentence_number><text>And I try to take my students also on this journey back into early time, to the beginnings of textiles.</text><page>52</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.115</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>18952</sentence_id><sentence_number>420</sentence_number><text>The 4 large projectors fitted with triple condensers are equipped with: r. revolving cross-frames for moving the slides vertically and horizontally, 2. a tall cylinder between the bellows and lens to move the 8 colour-keys up and down, J. a dynamic (iris-) diaphragm to regulate the intensity of the light and the light-effects.</text><page>19</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>18701</sentence_id><sentence_number>169</sentence_number><text>Until photography was invented, painting combined within itself the missions ui representation and expression in colour.</text><page>5</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.086</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>18638</sentence_id><sentence_number>106</sentence_number><text>Each of these elements may be moved in the desired direction and at the desired speed, enlarged or reduced, projected more brightly or more darkly, with sharp or unsharp outlines, can change colour, can merge with other coloured forms so that optical mixtures occur at the points where the colours overlap (e.g., red and blue become purple).</text><page>78</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>-0.075</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>18628</sentence_id><sentence_number>96</sentence_number><text>This principle has already been applied in a few scientific experiments, as in the study of movements (walking, jumping, galloping) and of zoological, botanical and mineral forms (enlargements, microscopic photographs) and other investigations into natural history; but these experiments have remained isolated phenomena, the inter­ connections of which have notbeenestablished(p. 50 to 56).</text><page>25</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>5751</sentence_id><sentence_number>13</sentence_number><text>The independence of the muscle function is, of course, relative.</text><page>14</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.05</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>13565</sentence_id><sentence_number>6395</sentence_number><text>By signs and forms, the artists express the unknown within us, to interpret the winding paths of the mind as really and efficiently as motion-curves serve scientific management.</text><page>126</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>-0.36700000000000005</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>13446</sentence_id><sentence_number>6276</sentence_number><text>Tbe water-fearing centuries bad caused all toilet apparatus to disappear from the dwelling rooms.</text><page>707</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>12755</sentence_id><sentence_number>5585</sentence_number><text>And inventiveness, formerly embodied in patent furniture, flows into mechanization of the household, where America takes the unchallenged lead.</text><page>523</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.068</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>12535</sentence_id><sentence_number>5365</sentence_number><text>For further insight into the process of movement, 49 F. B. Gilhreth, Primer of Scientific Management, New York, 1914, p.7.</text><page>115</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.025</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>12389</sentence_id><sentence_number>5219</sentence_number><text>After the perfecting of line production 0/Tr~.«hiTWry, full mechanization was applied to so delicate a material as pouUry.</text><page>140</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.05</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>11935</sentence_id><sentence_number>4765</sentence_number><text>The treatise in which Nicolas Oresme achieves this, the treatise On lnl£nsities,&apos; proceeds after the Aristotelian fashion from the general investiga­ tion of the qualities and quantities of an object.</text><page>29</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>-0.05</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>11359</sentence_id><sentence_number>4189</sentence_number><text>Climbing from below- he was the thirteenth child of a poor family- armed with an uuhreak­ ing will to conquer, and possessing a flair for success, he exemplifies in every trait the type of the nineteenth-century entrepreneur.</text><page>50</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.033</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>11274</sentence_id><sentence_number>4104</sentence_number><text>Only thoroughly fresh bread is tDlerated in the home - a factor conducive to waste.</text><page>212</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.035</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>11255</sentence_id><sentence_number>4085</sentence_number><text>Not until the end of the Gothic, when architecture had long been accustomed to hollow out interior space to the utm&lt;h&apos;t and to make the pillars slender almost to breaking point, did the massive wooden wall begin I&lt;&gt; dissolve into a lighter framework, The fifteenth century carried the process further, Then furniture was treated as a skeleton, like the frame of a house, The massive plank walls broke down into a system of horizontal ties and vertical supports, Assembled according to carpenters&apos; practice, their joints were carefully dovetailed, As in house construction, light, non-supporting panels were readily inserted into the frame in lieu of the wooden wall (fig, 150), Late Gothic frame construction grew organically from tl&gt;e properties of wood, It allows for swelling and for shrinking, It is as vital to the development of Ia ler furniture types as is the sustained development of the cross-ribbed vault in architecture - a flight from massiveness toward refinement of form, In detail, frame construction underwent many change ..</text><page>294</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.18100000000000002</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>11251</sentence_id><sentence_number>4081</sentence_number><text>Precisely when he sent his first carload from Chicago to Boston is not certain, but it was either in 1867 or 1868.</text><page>234</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.28600000000000003</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>11187</sentence_id><sentence_number>4017</sentence_number><text>-~COPYRIGHT 1948 by Oxford University Press, Inc. All rights reserved, including the right to reproduce this hook or portions thereof in any form.</text><page>3</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>-0.078</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10875</sentence_id><sentence_number>3705</sentence_number><text>xxn, Oct. 1931, which includes a list of the American patents down to 1836.</text><page>546</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10775</sentence_id><sentence_number>3605</sentence_number><text>Locks for post-office boxes were to he equipped in this way.</text><page>80</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.75</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10499</sentence_id><sentence_number>3329</sentence_number><text>The rail and carriage seemed the most perfect means of transportation.</text><page>91</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10436</sentence_id><sentence_number>3266</sentence_number><text>The legs are hinged so that they can be folded up.&apos;</text><page>339</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.1</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10406</sentence_id><sentence_number>3236</sentence_number><text>A gutta percha tube directly connected this &apos;gas-iron&apos; to the outlet in the ceiling (fig.</text><page>584</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.05</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10405</sentence_id><sentence_number>3235</sentence_number><text>An advertising leaflet in the Edison Institute, Dearborn, shows how the early &apos;fifties attempted to use gas as a constant heat source.</text><page>584</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.25</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10203</sentence_id><sentence_number>3033</sentence_number><text>ton&apos;s &apos;Reclining Woman&apos; of Divans penetrated public places, too, although in the more austere shape of upholstered benches.</text><page>385</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.193</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10052</sentence_id><sentence_number>2882</sentence_number><text>All you have to do is to push a very light tool over the floor,&apos; and it is assured, with a dig at the portahle electric types, &apos;it never wears out, will last as long as your building ... hetter results without any machinery ... no dirty 421.</text><page>606</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.25</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>10021</sentence_id><sentence_number>2851</sentence_number><text>Interest in the rapid conversion of the animal into meat centered from the first around the pig.</text><page>241</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.018000000000000002</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>9676</sentence_id><sentence_number>2506</sentence_number><text>Frt;;s. 289) The Decay of Regeneration Regeneration in the Middle Ages Twice, first at the beginning of the Middle A.ges and again at their close, the peoples of Western Europe came in contact with other customs of regenera­ tion: In the decline of the Ancient World, when the land-hungry nomads plundered Rome; and again some nine centuries later, when the Moors were finally driven from Spain around A.D. 1500.</text><page>666</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>-0.025</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>9517</sentence_id><sentence_number>2347</sentence_number><text>Beneath these furry textures, which clothe cushions flat or cylindrical, the woodwork decays like fallen trees obliterated beneath blankets of moss.</text><page>379</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.5</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>9215</sentence_id><sentence_number>2045</sentence_number><text>Urquhart was in love with the Orient and pledged to its cause.</text><page>682</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>8840</sentence_id><sentence_number>1670</sentence_number><text>In Alexandria we already find mechanisms being released by 3 Encyclopedie ou Dictionnaire raisonne, vol.</text><page>48</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>8802</sentence_id><sentence_number>1632</sentence_number><text>It has elaborated the elements already present in the &apos;variety couch&apos; of 1838.</text><page>425</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.05</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>8332</sentence_id><sentence_number>1162</sentence_number><text>With her sister, Harriet Beecher StDwe, author of Uncle Tom&apos;s Cabin, she completely rewrote her textbook on domestic economy.</text><page>528</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>7474</sentence_id><sentence_number>304</sentence_number><text>Among them was the Dutch­ man, Mart Stam; in one of his houses tubular steel chairs were seen, having not four legs but two.</text><page>506</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>22296</sentence_id><sentence_number>1460</sentence_number><text>U Utopia 18</text><page>47</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.133</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>22234</sentence_id><sentence_number>1398</sentence_number><text> This is the realistic basis of the workshop training.</text><page>12</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>22181</sentence_id><sentence_number>1345</sentence_number><text>Airplane views are macrophotogrophs: &quot;space compressors,’ an extension of observation. They reveal the large-scale relationships, as microphotographs reveal the smallest.</text><page>14</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.1</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>22038</sentence_id><sentence_number>1202</sentence_number><text>He was a passionate advocate of a new kind of art, to be based on tactile sensations alone, and proposed tactile ribbons, carpets, beds, rooms, stage-settings, etc.</text><page>13</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.25</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>21956</sentence_id><sentence_number>1120</sentence_number><text>This is the point at which one might insert the question of the effect of spatial values on sensory reactions, or even that of space perception.</text><page>32</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.013999999999999999</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>21776</sentence_id><sentence_number>940</sentence_number><text>An actual realization of equipoised sculpture can be made through the application of magnetic forces, or with electric remote control.</text><page>24</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>21542</sentence_id><sentence_number>706</sentence_number><text>build, not only upon practical considerations of its suitability for use, its material, construction, and economy; the experience of space belongs to the list too, as a psychological need.*</text><page>31</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.33299999999999996</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>21444</sentence_id><sentence_number>608</sentence_number><text>He thinks of outward security, instead of his inner satisfactions.</text><page>8</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.145</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>21398</sentence_id><sentence_number>562</sentence_number><text>Laden with false expectations, people want to “understand” everything at once, instead of first clearing the channels of experience.</text><page>17</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>-0.25</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>21290</sentence_id><sentence_number>454</sentence_number><text>A fancied increase in value was usually derived from imitation of an authentic arrangement, a mechanical repetition of a genuine historic form.</text><page>16</page><type>question</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>21101</sentence_id><sentence_number>265</sentence_number><text>The first steps toward such a concept were made intuitively by the constructivist painters.</text><page>20</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.133</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>20950</sentence_id><sentence_number>114</sentence_number><text>Vaudeville, circus, stage, cinema, and light display can be of the same order of space creation.</text><page>29</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.05</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>26314</sentence_id><sentence_number>609</sentence_number><text>In fact, no materializing of external forms expresses the content of a work 1 of painting but, rather, the forces=tensions which are alive within it.</text><page>36</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>26151</sentence_id><sentence_number>446</sentence_number><text>My task is out relationships between the to point &quot;organic&quot; elements of painting.</text><page>82</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>26043</sentence_id><sentence_number>338</sentence_number><text>From this last standpoint, the sum of the nations would form not a dissonance but rather, harmony.</text><page>84</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>25936</sentence_id><sentence_number>231</sentence_number><text>The geometric point is Therefore, it must be defined as The Geometric incorporeal thing.</text><page>28</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.225</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>25914</sentence_id><sentence_number>209</sentence_number><text>points + Result: I. inner sound of a point, 2. repetition of the sound, 3. double sound of the first point, 4. double sound of the second point, sound of 5. the sum of all these sounds.</text><page>41</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.079</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>25903</sentence_id><sentence_number>198</sentence_number><text>These three types are the purest forms of straight lines and they are differ- Tempera- ture entiated from each other by temperature: 1. cold form, Most concise forms of Endless 2. warm form, the potentiality for movement.</text><page>66</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.174</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>25887</sentence_id><sentence_number>182</sentence_number><text>[This book has recently been translated into English and 76, reissued under the title &quot;On the Spiritual Art&quot; the Solomon Guggenheim in by R. Foundation, New York City, this particular reference will be found and on pages 60 to 64, inch] A cautious use of these concepts is especially important in the analysis of &quot;form in drawing,&quot; since it is right here that direction plays a definite role.</text><page>65</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>2384</sentence_id><sentence_number>1231</sentence_number><text>For this reason wire-mesh, lattice- shapes were made transparent, through the use of plastics, glass, motion I work and perforated metal sheets.</text><page>41</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>2380</sentence_id><sentence_number>1227</sentence_number><text>wood, glass, nickel- (See page 44: Nickel sculpture, 1921.)</text><page>41</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.136</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>2119</sentence_id><sentence_number>966</sentence_number><text>Simultaneously with the sculptures made from metal and glass, I turned toward the new industrial materials.</text><page>42</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.033</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>1989</sentence_id><sentence_number>836</sentence_number><text>of the the thickness \ formed by weather cock, of the same wire of the curved with similarly when combined which, space curves produced space row of into a complete blended could be of the edges, the thickness gauge as on the edges, emphasis plastics, with transparent partly made of were cells.</text><page>44</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>1988</sentence_id><sentence_number>835</sentence_number><text>which surfaces the curved only through spatial effects, not produced &quot;modulators&quot; directions in all lines flowing through the but also or receding, either protruding were edges Their sheets themselves.</text><page>44</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.353</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>1983</sentence_id><sentence_number>830</sentence_number><text>more resistant to structurally the plastics curves made bends and The of the light 1 made a part could be high lights.</text><page>44</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.433</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>1979</sentence_id><sentence_number>826</sentence_number><text>can be easily when heated, plastics, Thus I heated, material.</text><page>44</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>1791</sentence_id><sentence_number>638</sentence_number><text>Der &quot;As a painter, typographer, photographer, stage-designer and architect he Plastics 86 is one 25.</text><page>47</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>-0.325</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>1677</sentence_id><sentence_number>524</sentence_number><text>In their need of getting metal away from a false ethos, from an excessive respect for fossilized works, their slogan bar floating between two glass plates.</text><page>24</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.0</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>1615</sentence_id><sentence_number>462</sentence_number><text>The next generation when glass and compressed air architecture develops.</text><page>33</page><type>text</type></item><item><sentiment_score>0.6</sentiment_score><color>#fbfbfb</color><sentence_id>1168</sentence_id><sentence_number>15</sentence_number><text>His wood was to stand for wood, his metal for metal, etc., ond have its own value.</text><page>23</page><type>text</type></item></sentences>